freeformatter.com 2019-04-06

# Privacy Statement - Freeformatter.com

Your privacy is important to FREEFORMATTER. This privacy statement provides information about the Personal Information that FREEFORMATTER collects, and the ways in which FREEFORMATTER uses that Personal Information.

## Personal Information collection

FREEFORMATTER may collect and use Personal Information about your use of this website, namely information about browsing and linking ("Personal Information");

The Tools available on FREEFORMATTER, namely, formatters, validators, encoders & decoders, code minifiers and beautifiers, converters, cryptography and security tools, string escapers and utilities, data generators and other web resources available on www.freeformatter.com (the "Tools") that require server side processing keep all the data in 'transient memory (RAM)' for a very short period of time. This data is not collected, stored or otherwise persisted.

Exceptionally, the "Batch Formatter" tool, which processes large files, requires the data to be temporarily stored on the cloud. This data is temporarily stored for a duration of up to 24 hours. There are policies in place for the removal of any data that persists on the cloud servers above this transient period. However, FREEFORMATTER does not make any representation or guarantee that these policies are applied as they are handled by the cloud server providers.

## Using Personal Information

FREEFORMATTER may use your Personal Information to:

  * administer this website;
  * enable your access to and use of the website services; and
  * improve the services it offers and monitor the traffic and Tools usage;

Cookies are strictly used for load balancing, clustering and session affinity. FREEFORMATTER does not track Sensitive Information or single users. Additionally, FREEFORMATTER uses third party add-ons including, but not limited to, Google Analytics, Amazon Web Services, Google+ and Facebook Social ("Third Party Add-Ons"). Such Third Party Addons may have different cookie policies and FREEFORMATTER does not control or administer the cookies dropped by these Third Party Add-Ons, and it is the user's responsibility to ensure his/her compliance with same.

No data or file uploaded on FREEFORMATTER's servers is read, analysed or similarly processed.

## Sensitive Information

Before submitting documents containing Sensitive Information such as information pertaining to someone's health, finances, proprietary data, security data, biometric data, or any information otherwise considered confidential ("Sensitive Information") users should obtain prior consent from their respective security officer, compliance officer or legal department to do so. 

FREEFORMATTER shall not be liable for any data uploaded by a user and any user that uploads Sensitive Information on freeformatter.com

## Disclosing your Personal Information

Where FREEFORMATTER discloses your Personal Information to its agents or sub-contractors for these purposes, the agent or sub-contractor in question will be obligated to use that Personal Information in accordance with the terms of this privacy statement.

In addition to the disclosures reasonably necessary for the purposes identified elsewhere above, FREEFORMATTER may disclose your Personal Information to the extent that it is required to do so by law, in connection with any legal proceedings or prospective legal proceedings, and in order to establish, exercise or defend its legal rights.

If FREEFORMATTER is being acquired or merges with another company, your information may be transferred to the new owners in order to facilitate ongoing operations

## Securing your data

FREEFORMATTER will take reasonable technical and organisational precautions to prevent the loss, unauthorized access, misuse, disclosure, alteration or destruction of your Personal Information.

FREEFORMATTER supports SSL (HTTPS) communications whenever applicable, with the intent of further protecting your privacy and further providing security for your data.

FREEFORMATTER will store all the Personal Information you provide on its secure servers. Security measures are based on open-source libraries which are not audited by FREEFORMATTER. FREEFORMATTER is not liable for any security flaws these security measures may have.

## Cross-border data transfers

Information that FREEFORMATTER collects may be stored and processed in and transferred between any of the countries in which FREEFORMATTER operates to enable the use of the information in accordance with this privacy policy.

You agree to such cross-border transfers of Personal Information.

## Updating this statement

FREEFORMATTER may update this privacy policy by posting a new version on this website. FREEFORMATTER will notify you of any changes by posting a new version of the Privacy Statement on this website.

You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are familiar with any changes.

## Other websites

This website contains links to other websites. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party's site. FREEFORMATTER is not responsible for the content and privacy practices of other websites and we strongly advise you to review the privacy policy of every third party site you visit.

## Contact FREEFORMATTER

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or FREEFORMATTER' treatment of your Personal Information, please write by email to: [freeformatter@gmail.com](mailto:freeformatter@gmail.com)
